Finding Aid for the Henry Miller Papers LSC.0110
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Manuscripts, 1896-1980; 33 boxes, 4.5 oversized boxes (18.5 linear ft.)
  - Literary manuscripts by Miller, 1896-1978; 22 boxes, 4.5 oversized boxes (13 linear ft.)
    - The Nightmare Notebook, 1940-1941; 1 items. (Box 97, Folder 11)
      Illustrated handwritten manuscript, titled in Miller's hand as "Notebook of American tour." Interspersed with drawings in crayon and preceded by several pages of watercolors. Notebook begins after 30 pages of Whitman's Leaves of Grass, and is bound.
    - Notes on D.H. Lawrence's Aaron's Rod, undated; 3 items. (Box 97, Folder 12)
      Typescript, 28 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers. Includes two pages of misc. manuscript notes.
    - "O Lake of Light", 1943 November 5; 1 items. (Box 97, Folder 13)
      Typescript and carbon copy poem with corrections. Holograph note explains dedication. Text of the poem sold to Harper's Bazaar.
    - Obscenity and the law of reflection, 1944; 5 items. (Box 97, Folder 14)
      Carbon typescript with holograph corrections, 21 leaves. Bound with a letter from Henry Miller to Oscar Baradinsky, publisher, and a copy of number one of the "Outcast" series of chapbooks in which this manuscript was reprinted.
    - "Obscenity in literature", 1953; 1 items. (Box 97, Folder 15)
      Three typescripts, 21 leaves each. Inscribed "Written expressly for Maitre Sev, Paris, to be used as testimony in the forthcoming trial of 'Sexus." Also includes two typescripts of another draft titled "Morality in Literature," 20 leaves each.
    - Of, by and about Henry Miller, circa 1946; 1 items. (Box 97, Folder 16)
      Typescript with holograph lists of Miller's prefaces, reviews, and essays. Includes a letter from Miller to Oscar Barandinsky concerning publication. Published by the Alicat Bookshop Press, Yonkers, 1947.
    - "Of art and the future", 1943 May-June; 3 items. (Box 97, Folder 17)
      Typescript with holograph annotations.
    - "The old neighborhood", 1964; 3 items. (Box 97, Folder 18)
      Two typescript drafts. Accompanied by a letter from Murray Fisher, associate editor of "Playboy," regarding the purchase of this piece. Published in "Playboy," December 1965.
    - "On creativity", undated; 1 items. (Box 98, Folder 1)
      Typescripts with annotations. Published by Playboy magazine in an article entitled "On Creativity," vol. 15, no. 12 (December 1968), p. 136-139.
    - "On Gertrude Stein", 1936; 1 items. (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - "On Lawrence Durrell", 1959 October 3; 1 items. (Box 98, Folder 3)
      Carbon typescripts with holograph corrections, written for Guenter Penzoldt to help launch the world premier of Durrell's Sappho in Hamburg. Includes a letter from Henry Miller to Lawrence Clark Powell dated 8 October 1959.
    - "On reading Homer", circa 1964; 1 items. (Box 98, Folder 4)
      Typescript with extensive holograph corrections, 5 leaves. Also includes 1 page of holograph notes. Published in the "International Henry Miller Letter," No. 6 (April 1964).
    - "On reading Homer." For French edition of The Odyssey, 1959; 1 items. (Box 98, Folder 5)
      Typescript, 5 leaves each.
    - "An open letter to private Alfred Perlès", undated; 18 items. (Box 98, Folder 6)
      Boxed typescript with holograph corrections, 43 leaves. Inscription: "In reply to his [Perlès'] open letter in the December, 1940 issue of 'Horizon,' London." Appears as Part 1 of Miller's Murder the Murderer (Bern Porter: Berkeley, 1944).
    - Open letters, circa 1937-1948; 1 items. (Box 98, Folder 7)
      Mimeographs and typescripts, includes "Announcement to art patrons" and "Promotion ideas of Beverly Glen days." "Special begging letter to celebrities!" was written with the editors of Booster.
    - Opus Pistorum (1 of 2), 1950; 1 items. (Box 98, Folder 8)
      Bound carbon typescript. For further information regarding this work, see Sipper, Ralph B. [letter to Lawrence Clark Powell], Santa Barbara, 14 June 1983 and see Howard, George [Papers], ca.1941-1947.
    - Opus Pistorum (2 of 2), 1950; 4 items. (Box 98, Folder 9)
      Bound carbon typescript. For further information regarding the this work, see Sipper, Ralph B. [letter to Lawrence Clark Powell], Santa Barbara, 14 June 1983 and see Howard, George [Papers], ca.1941-1947.
    - Order and Chaos Chez Hans Reichel. Broadside and publicity drafts, 1966; 1 items. (Box 98, Folder 10)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, and assorted printed materials and notes.
    - Order and Chaos Chez Hans Reichel. Corrected galley proofs, 1966; ca. 100 items. (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - Order and Chaos Chez Hans Reichel. Correspondence between Henry Miller and Loujon Press. (1 of 2), 1965-1967; ca. 130 items. (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - Order and Chaos Chez Hans Reichel. Correspondence between Henry Miller and Loujon Press. (2 of 2), 1966-1967; 8 items. (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Order and Chaos Chez Hans Reichel. Illustrations and cover design, photographs, circa 1966; 5 items. (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Order and Chaos Chez Hans Reichel. Introduction by Laurence Durrell, 1966 (Box 99, Folder 3)
      Typescript with corrections. Includes correspondence between Durrell and the Loujon Press.
    - Order and Chaos Chez Hans Reichel. Loujon Press photocopy of original manuscript, circa 1966; 1 items. (Box 99, Folder 4)
      Original manuscript was written in 1937-1938 and presented, in manuscript form, to Miller's friend Hans Reichel. The Loujon Press prepared its edition of Order and Chaos using this photocopy of Reichel's original.
    - Order and Chaos Chez Hans Reichel. Record print from microfilm, 1937; 1 items. (Box 99, Folder 5)
      Copy made from the Library's negative microfilm of the original holograph manuscript. Miller wrote and illustrated this book for his art teacher, Hans Reichel.
    - Order and Chaos Chez Hans Reichel. Typescript, circa 1966; 2 items. (Box 99, Folder 6)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, 78 leaves. Notes and letters by Henry Miller interspersed. Includes original script, postscript and French section. Published by Loujon Press, Tucson, AZ, 1966.
    - Order and Chaos Chez Hans Reichel. Typescripts from Emil Schnellcock's Papers, undated; 1 items. (Box 99, Folder 7)
      1 typescripts, pages 9-11 only. 3 leaves. 1 Typescript, pages 9-11 only. 3 leaves.
    - "Palace of entrails", undated; 1 items. (Box 99, Folder 8)
      Typescript, 4 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - Patchen: Man of Anger and Light, 1946; 1 items. (Box 99, Folder 9)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, entitled "Patchen preface and notes." In a manila paper folder with watercolor illustration. Also includes 6 leaves of holograph notes, 20 leaves of typescript with holograph corrections in ink and corrections in pen.
    - "Peace and putrefaction", undated; 2 items. (Box 99, Folder 10)
      Carbon typescript. From the book Hamlet, letter dated October 17, 1938.
    - Personal mailing list and list of bookshops, undated; 1 items. (Box 99, Folder 11)
      Carbon typescript with holograph corrections.
    - "Places to visit", undated; 1 items. (Box 99, Folder 12)
      Typescript, 4 leaves. A list of places, mostly churches, missions, and humanitarian associations, and a description of the services provided.
    - Stand Still Like the Hummingbird. "Lime twigs and treachery", 1957; 2 items. (Box 100, Folder 1)
      Two typescript drafts. Published in "Stand Still Like the Hummingbird," New Directions, 1962.
    - Stand Still Like the Hummingbird. "Open sesame!", 1954; 2 items. (Box 100, Folder 2)
      Assorted typescript drafts. Early draft entitled "Less Books, Better Readers." Also includes letter from Henry Geiger to Miller and two news-letters written by Helene Scheu-Riesz.
    - Stand Still Like the Humming Bird. "Preface", 1959; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 3)
      Typescripts with extensive holograph annotations. Includes first and second draft.
    - Stand Still Like the Humming Bird. "Stand still like the humming bird", 1959; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 4)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, 16 leaves. Note reads: "To appear in 'Noonday Review.'"
    - Sunday After the War. "Art and the future", undated; 2 items. (Box 100, Folder 5)
      Typescript with holograph corrections. Inscribed: "Bern Porter--here's a corrected ms. Copy for you as token of my esteem."
    - Sunday After the War. "More About Anaïs Nin.", 1944; 3 items. (Box 100, Folder 6)
      Mimeograph and typescript copy. Manuscript entitled "Letter to Anaïs Nin regarding one of her books." Published by New Directions, Norfolk, 1944. This is the second letter in a series of two. Typescript copy dated Clichy, 1933.
    - Sunday After the War. "The most lovely inanimate object in existence", undated; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 7)
      Photocopies of typescripts with holograph corrections. Intended for The Air-Conditioned Nightmare but not used. Published in the Harvard Advocate ca. 1944 as "Sunday after the War," and again in Remember to Remember (New York: New Directions, 1947).
    - "Tahiti", undated; 2 items. (Box 100, Folder 8)
      Holograph manuscript with corrections, 5 leaves. Initialed by the author.
    - Corrections to F. Jacques Temple's book on Henry Miller and accompanying letter, 1965 June; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 9)
      Holograph and carbon typescript. Miller's corrections to Temple's book Henry Miller (Paris: Deforges, c1977). Includes a copy of Miller's letter to Temple, incorporating the corrections.
    - "Text for proposed Doubleday album", undated; 3 items. (Box 100, Folder 10)
      Typescript with holograph annotations, 20 leaves. Preface for proposed reproduction of Miller's artwork in book form.
    - "Text to accompany photo taken by Margo Moore", 1972; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 11)
      Typescript, 2 leaves and a holograph draft, 3 leaves. Includes a letter from Margo Moore to Miller.
    - The Time of the Assassins. "Preface", 1955 May 15; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 12)
    - "To me it would seem that the Japanese woman...", undated; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 13)
      Holograph on white laid paper. Signed by the author.
    - To Paint is to Love Again. [Galley proofs], undated; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 14)
      Proofs for American Pocketbook edition.
    - To Paint is to Love Again. Spanish translation by Constanza Camargo Junguito, 1952; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 15)
    - Transcription of Dante, undated; 2 items. (Box 100, Folder 16)
      Holograph manuscript, 2 leaves. Sent to Robert Osborn, with Miller's inscription: "Here's a bit of Dante in French--which someone dictated to me as a lesson."
    - Tropic of Capricorn. "I am a wild park", undated; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 17)
      Typescripts, 5 leaves. Penciled inscription by Bern Porter reads "A piece often read aloud by H. M. to friends...." Published by the Obelisk Press, Paris, 1939. Also printed in Booster, no. 2, vol. 8 (Oct. 1937).
    - Tropic of Capricorn and Tropic of Cancer. Galley proofs for Italian editions, 1961; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 18)
      335 leaves. Galley proofs with extensive corrections for the Gianagicacomo Feltrinelli Editore edition of the Italian translations of Tropico del Cancro and Tropico del Capricorno. Bound in wrappers.
    - Tropic of Capricorn. Galleys (incomplete), undated; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 19)
      3 pages.
    - Tropic of Capricorn. "On the ovarian trolley", 1938; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 20)
      Typescript. 15 leaves.
    - Unidentified lists and notes, undated; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 21)
      Holograph, 5 leaves.
    - "Vignettes of Paris", undated; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 22)
      Carbon typescripts and ephemera. Stories entitled: "Gobelins tapestries," "Paris in ut-mineur," "Street in fog," and "The cirque medrano."
    - "Villa Seurat, 30 Octobre 37" [Miscellaneous fragment], 1937; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 23)
      Typescript, 1 leaf. Three signatures, one of which is H. Miller.
    - "Walt Whitman", undated; 4 items. (Box 100, Folder 24)
    - The Waters Reglitterized, 1939-1949; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 25)
      Typescripts with holograph corrections, and layouts. Text from letters written by Henry Miller to Emil Schnellock. Preface added and written in 1949. Published by John Kidis, San Jose, 1950. Includes photographs of watercolors.
    - "What am I doing here?", undated; 3 items. (Box 100, Folder 26)
      Typescript with holograph annotations. Manuscript titled "Who am I? Where am I--What am I doing here?" Published in Holiday magazine, 43:6 (June 1968), p. 46.
    - What are you going to do about Alf?, 1944; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 27)
      Page proofs, layouts, and sample pages with corrections by Bern Porter. Published by Bern Porter, Berkeley, 1944.
    - "Whatever you do, don't think!", undated; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 28)
      Holograph, 3 leaves.
    - The Wisdom of the Heart. "Benno, the wild man from Borneo", undated; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 29)
      Originally entitled, "Chez Benno, the Man From Borneo," typescript with holograph notes, 5 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - The Wisdom of the Heart. "The enormous womb", undated; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 30)
      Typescript, 10 leaves. Revised after its appearance in "Booster," 4.10-11 (December 1937): 20-24. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - The Wisdom of the Heart. "Raimu", circa 1939; 2 items. (Box 100, Folder 31)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, 15 leaves.
    - Wisdom of the Heart. "Uterine hunger", circa 1933; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 32)
      Carbon typescript. Originally intended for a book titled Plasma and Magma. Two versions: one published by New Directions, Norfolk, 1941; another in Paris, December 1933.
    - "With the wine merchants", 1930; 1 items. (Box 100, Folder 33)
    - "A word about Abraham Rattner", undated; 6 items. (Box 100, Folder 34)
      Holograph with corrections.
    - "Brochure." Volume 1. Photocopy, circa 1933; 1 items. (Box 105, Folder 1)
      Oversized.
    - Plexus. Photocopies, p. 700-899, circa 1950; 4 items. (Box 106, Folder 1)
      Oversized. Inscribed: "Retyped-pages checked are still to be retyped-some improved."
    - Paris notebooks. 3 volumes. Photocopy, 1933-1935; 1 items. (Box 106, Folder 2)
      Oversized. Photocopy of holograph and typescript manuscript.
    - The World of Lawrence. Excerpts and original draft, undated; 1 items. (Box 140, Folder 1)
      Typescripts in marble letter box. Available on negative microfilm no. 05988.
    - The World of Lawrence. Excerpts from the writings and correspondence of Lawrence, undated; 1 items. (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - The World of Lawrence. Random notes and correspondence, undated; 1 items. (Box 141, Folder 1)
      In marble letter box. Available on negative microfilm no. 05988.
    - The World of Lawrence. "Finished pages and notes", undated; 1 items. (Box 141, Folder 2)
      Typescript. Available in the Negative Microfilm Collection.
    - The World of Lawrence. Bound typescirpt draft, undated; 1 items. (Box 141, Folder 3)
      Title page inscription: "Begun at Clichy as a brochure of 100 pages..." Last section consists of random notes and excerpts from Lawrence's works.
    - The World of Sex. "First rewrite", 1957; 2 items. (Box 142, Folder 1)
      "First draft," 2 typescripts, 77 leaves each.
    - The World of Sex. "Second rewrite", 1957; 1 items. (Box 142, Folder 2)
      Two typescripts, 67 leaves each.
    - "The writer's emergency fund", 1941; 1 items. (Box 142, Folder 3)
      Typescript, 5 leaves. Open letter written by Miller on behalf of "writers who are in distress."
    - "Written in the diary of Anaïs Nin", undated; 1 items. (Box 142, Folder 4)
      Unpublished typescript. Available on negative microfilm no. 07115.
    - "Wynn Bullock", undated (Box 142, Folder 5)
      Typescript, 2 leaves. Published in "Monterey Peninsula and Big Sur: A Guide," Emil White, 1955.
    - Plexus. Early version, p. 700-1399, circa 1950 (Box 154, Folder 1)
      Incomplete carbon typescript with extensive holograph annotations.
    - Plexus. "Discarded pages," p. 700-1399, circa 1950; 1 items. (Box 154, Folder 2)
    - Plexus. Incomplete typescript, p. 700-1368, circa 1950; 1 items. (Box 154, Folder 3)
    - Plexus. "Second carbon, latest," p. 700-1370, circa 1950; 1 items. (Box 154, Folder 4)
    - Plexus. "Discarded pages from the last rewrite," p. 700-1370, circa 1950; 1 items. (Box 155, Folder 1)
      Incomplete typescript with extensive holograph corrections.
    - Plexus. "Mss. pages, Plexus," p. 700-1370A, circa 1950; 1 items. (Box 155, Folder 2)
      Incomplete carbon typescript of the final draft on green and yellow paper.
    - The Plight of the Creative Artist in the United States of America, circa 1944; 2 items. (Box 155, Folder 4)
      Layout dummy, notes, letter to Bern Porter and a mimeographed typescript. Includes one page of notes from Miller to Bern Porter and a letter from James T. Farrell to Bern Porter requesting permission to quote Farrell in "Open letter to all and sundry."
    - "Portrait of General Grant", 1935; 2 items. (Box 155, Folder 5)
      Typescripts with holograph corrections. Published in Night and Day, December 23 1937.
    - "Preface to the new water color album", 1964; 1 items. (Box 155, Folder 6)
      Two typescripts, 3 leaves each.
    - "Promenade without spats", 1931; 4 items. (Box 155, Folder 7)
    - Quiet Days in Clichy. "Quiet days in Clichy" and "Mara-Marigan marinated", 1956; 1 items. (Box 155, Folder 8)
      Three typescripts that include both "Quiet days in Clichy" and "Mara-Marigan Marinated." Another typescript with holgoraph corrections of "Mara-Marigan marinated" alone. Originally written in 1940. Rewritten in Big Sur, 1956.
    - "Rainer Maria Rilke", undated; 2 items. (Box 156, Folder 1)
      Typescript. 13 leaves. Includes note to Emil Schnellock explaining that Miller co-wrote this piece with Alfred Perlès. Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - "The Rattner portfolio", 1957; 2 items. (Box 156, Folder 2)
      Two typescript drafts.
    - "Recollections of Avignon", 1954; 8 items. (Box 156, Folder 3)
      Two typescripts, one with holograph corrections.
    - Recommendation of Angelos Sikelianos for the Nobel Prize. Typescripts of "The Delphic Union," etc., 1946; 1 items. (Box 156, Folder 4)
      Three drafts of Miller's recommendation of Sikelianos for the Nobel prize addressed to the members of the Stockholm Academy. Also, two telegrams from Eva Sikelianos to Miller and Miller' list of possible signatories.
    - The Red Notebook, circa 1958; 1 items. (Box 156, Folder 5)
      Bound holograph manuscript composed of lists of names, places, book titles, watercolors, quotations, excerpts and itineraries in ink and pencil. Includes astrological charts and photographs, and occasional sketches in ink, crayon and watercolor.
    - The Red Notebook. Photographs of original holograph notebook, circa 1958; 1 items. (Box 156, Folder 6)
      Images reduced in size to 10 x 7 cm., and mounted on 22 sheets of cardboard.
    - [Regarding the diary of Anaïs Nin], 1937; 1 items. (Box 156, Folder 7)
      Typescript with holograph notes, 30 leaves. Missing page 1. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - "Reichel is as Reichel was", 1962; 2 items. (Box 156, Folder 8)
    - Remember to Remember. "A Bodhisattva artist", 1944-1945; 3 items. (Box 156, Folder 9)
      Carbon typescripts with holograph corrections. Labeled "Coda to...".
    - Remember to Remember. "Astrological fricassee", circa 1944; 4 items. (Box 156, Folder 10)
      Assorted typescripts. Titles include: "Hello April 26th! Yoohoo!," "Hello June! Yoohoo!," and "Astrological fricassee." Also published in Miller's Nights of Love and Laughter (New York: New American Library, 1955).
    - Remember to Remember. "Murder the murderer", undated; 2 items. (Box 156, Folder 11)
      Typescripts with holograph corrections. Assorted versions. Also published as a pamphlet entitled Murder the Murderer (Berkeley: Bern Porter, 1944).
    - Preface to Remember to Remember. "Preface", undated; 1 items. (Box 157, Folder 1)
      Incomplete typescript with holograph corrections, boxes in a red linen case. Includes a carbon typescript draft.
    - Remember to Remember. "The staff of life", 1944-1945; 1 items. (Box 157, Folder 2)
      Typescript with holograph corrections. In a manila folder with an illustrated watercolor cover.
    - Remember to Remember. "Varda: the master builder", 1944-1945; 3 items. (Box 157, Folder 3)
    - "Revolt in the desert", undated; 1 items. (Box 157, Folder 4)
      Two typescript drafts, 8 leaves. Also includes "List for Cavalier," a list of names and address.
    - Translation of Jean Nicolas Arthur Rimbaud's A Season in Hell. Incomplete holograph manuscript, 1945; 4 items. (Box 157, Folder 5)
      In a manila folder with an illustrated watercolor cover. Includes excerpts from Jacques Riviere's Rimbaud, plus material (poems, "deliriums," list of words, notes) which do not pertain to Rimbaud.
    - Translation of Jean Nicolas Arthur Rimbaud's A Season in Hell. Assorted typescripts, circa 1950; 1 items. (Box 157, Folder 6)
    - Translation of Jean Nicolas Arthur Rimbaud's A Season in Hell. Final draft, circa 1950; 3 items. (Box 157, Folder 7)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, 18 leaves, boxed in a red linen case.
    - "Rimbaud opus." Correspondence, typescripts of critical comments on Roger-Cornaz's translation of Miller's Rimbaud, 1949-1950; 9 items. (Box 157, Folder 8)
      Correspondence between Miller and Fred Roger-Cornaz concerning the latter's translation of Miller's Rimbaud works. Miller's critical commentary on the Roger-Cornaz translation of the Rimbaud Opus, Parts 1 and 2.
    - "Rimbaud opus." Miscellaneous materials, 1947; 3 items. (Box 157, Folder 9)
      Assorted typescripts and notes.
    - "Rimbaud opus, part 2: when do angels cease to resemble themselves?", 1949?; 1 items. (Box 157, Folder 10)
      Typescripts with holograph corrections, each ca. 60 leaves. In a manila folder with an illustrated watercolor cover. Titled "Part 2: When do angels cease to resemble themselves?" Published in New Directions Year Book no. 11, 1949 under the title "Rimbaud.
    - "The Romans and the Wops", 1930; 1 items. (Box 157, Folder 11)
    - "Saga of the streets--apotheosis", undated (Box 157, Folder 12)
      Typescript, 7 leaves. Inscribed "Part of Part 2."
    - "Self-portrait", undated; 4 items. (Box 157, Folder 13)
      Typescript, ca. 21 leaves. From Emil Schnellock's Papers.
    - "Salute to Ephraim Doner", undated; 1 items. (Box 157, Folder 14)
      Typescripts with extensive annotations.
    - "Salute with fire and bugle to another immortal", 1954; 2 items. (Box 157, Folder 15)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, 8 leaves. Entitled "Cendrars text for 'Risques.'"
    - Semblance of a Devoted Past, circa 1945; 3 items. (Box 158, Folder 1)
      Typescripts with holograph annotations and printer's markings.
    - Semblance of a Devoted Past. Page proofs, circa 1945; 1 items. (Box 158, Folder 2)
      Page proofs with printer's markings. Text taken from letters written by Henry Miller to Emil Schnellock, 1922-1939. Published by Bern Porter, Berkeley, 1945.
    - Semblance of a Devoted Past. Layouts, galley proofs, and letters to Bern Porter from George Van Vechten, 1944; 17 items. (Box 158, Folder 3)
      Production materials.
    - Letters to Emil Schnellock. Typescript (1 of 6), circa 1922-1926; 18 items. (Box 158, Folder 4)
      Selections from these letters were used as text in Miller's Semblance of a Devoted Past (Berkley: Bern Porter, 1944) and in Miller's The Waters Reglitterized (San Jose: John Kiddiss, 1950). See also Series I for correspondence with Emil Schnellock.